Guide to the Lloyd A. Fallers Papers 1937-1977
University of Chicago Library
- Series VIII: International Encyclopedia of the Social Sciences
  - Smith, Raymond T., 1962-1963 (Box 50, Folder 2)
  - Stanner, W. E. H., n.d. (Box 50, Folder 3)
  - Steward, Julian H., 1964 (Box 50, Folder 4)
  - T, general, 1962-1966 (Box 50, Folder 5)
  - V, general, 1963-1965 (Box 50, Folder 6)
  - Vallier, Ivan and Vivian, 1966-1967 (Box 50, Folder 7)
  - W, general, 1962-1965 (Box 50, Folder 8)
  - Wax, Rosalie H., 1963-1964 (Box 50, Folder 9)
  - Weinreich, Uriel, 1962-1965 (Box 50, Folder 10)
  - White, Leslie A., 1964 (Box 50, Folder 11)
  - Wold, Herman O., 1966 (Box 50, Folder 12)
  - Y, general, 1963-1965 (Box 50, Folder 13)
  - Unidentified, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 14-15)
- Series IX: Margaret Chave Fallers Papers
  Series IX, Margaret Chave Fallers Papers, Boxes 50 to 53, contains field notes by Mrs. Fallers (then Margaret Elinor Chave) taken during the summer of 1947 on Majuro, an atoll in the southern Marshall Islands, and a subseries containing general material associated with this project. Her study was carried out under the combined auspices of the University of Hawaii and the Pacific Science Board's Coordinated Investigation of Micronesian Anthropology. This research formed the basis for her A.M. thesis, "The Changing Position of the Mixed-Bloods in the Marshall Islands" which was submitted to the Department of Anthropology, University of Chicago in 1948. The Miscellaneous subseries is composed of manuscripts based both on Mrs. Fallers' research in Africa and on her experience as principal of the high school at the Laboratory Schools (1968-1971).
  - Subseries 1: Marshall Islands
    - Sub-subseries 1: General Files
      - Lecture, notes, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 16)
      - Reading notes, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 17)
      - "Interim Report, Majuro, Marshall Islands, Margaret Chave, Coordinated Investigation of Micronesian Anthropology Project, University of Hawaii, "1947 (Box 50, Folder 18)
      - Correspondence, 1947-1948 (Box 50, Folder 19)
      - Coordinated Investigation of Micronesian Anthropology, Pacific Science Board, National Research Council, bulletins, 1947-1948 (Box 50, Folder 20)
      - Erdland, P. A., "Die Marshall-Insulaner, " translation, 1914 (Box 51, Folder 1)
      - Keesing, Felix M., "The Status of Persons of Mixed Descent in the Pacific Area, " manuscript, n.d. (Box 51, Folder 2)
      - Kramer, Augustin, "Hawaii, Ostmikronesien und Samoa, " translation, 1906 (Box 51, Folder 3)
      - Mason, Leonard E., "The Economic Organization of the Marshall Islanders, "1947 (Box 51, Folder 4)
      - An Ethnological Survey, " class paper, 1948 (Box 51, Folder 5)
      - Chicago Natural History Museum1947 Ethnological Expedition to Micronesia," manuscript, n.d. (Box 51, Folder 6)
      - Thilenius, G., "Results of the South Sea Expedition 1908-1910, Marshall Islands, Volume 11, " translation, 1938 (Box 51, Folder 7)
      - United States Commercial Company, Economic Survey, Maps of the Islands of Micronesia Under Administration of U.S. Naval Military Government Pacific Ocean Areas, 1946 (Box 51, Folder 8)
      - A Selected Bibliography of Bibliographies, "1946 (Box 51, Folder 9)
      - United States Naval Military Government Unit, Majuro, English Reader for the Marshallese People, 1944, 1946 (Box 51, Folder 10)
      - United States Naval Military Government Unit, Majuro, quarterly report, June 30, 1947 (Box 51, Folder 11)
      - United States Naval Military Government Unit, Majuro, monthly reports, 1947 (Box 51, Folder 12)
      - United States Naval Military Government Unit, Majuro, memoranda, 1947 (Box 51, Folder 13)
      - United States Pacific Fleet and Pacific Ocean Areas, District Intelligence Office, 14th Naval District in cooperation with Commander Marshalls-Gilberts Area, Marshallese-English and English-Marshallese Dictionary with notes on Pronunciation and Grammar, 1945 (Box 52, Folder 1-2)
      - Clippings, 1947-1948 (Box 52, Folder 3)
      - Miscellaneous, 1947 (Box 52, Folder 4)
    - Sub-subseries 2: Field notes, Majuro Atoll, 1947
      - Church, mission, reprint, 1945 (Box 52, Folder 5)
      - Demons, fauna, taboo, war, weapons (Box 52, Folder 6)
      - Food, clothing (Box 52, Folder 7)
      - Games, music (Box 52, Folder 8)
      - Handcrafts (Box 52, Folder 9)
      - Mixed-blood, genealogies (Box 52, Folder 10)
      - Myths, beliefs, folk tales (Box 52, Folder 11-12)
      - People (Box 52, Folder 13)
      - Political organization (Box 52, Folder 14)
      - Sailing, fishing (Box 52, Folder 15)
      - School (Box 52, Folder 16)
      - Sickness, medicine (Box 53, Folder 1)
      - Social organization (Box 53, Folder 2)
      - Stores (Box 53, Folder 3)
      - Stories (Box 53, Folder 4)
      - United States Navy (Box 53, Folder 5)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 53, Folder 6)
  - Subseries 2: Miscellaneous
    - "The Eastern Lacustrine Bantu (Ganda and Soga), "n.d. (Box 53, Folder 7)
    - "The Need for Work and Service Experiences for Young People of Illinois, Ages 14-24, " manuscript, 1974 (Box 53, Folder 8)
    - A Working Paper for Discussion, " manuscript, 1974 (Box 53, Folder 9)
- Series X: Microfilms
  Series X, Microfilms (Box 54), contains information concerning Fallers' work in Africa and of particular note is the collection and translations of Luganda texts. The microfilm contained in the series is restricted due to the need for special equipment.
  - Buganda study, leadership questionnaries, n.d. (Box 54, Reel 1)
  - Ashe, R.P., Two Kings of Uganda, London, ca.1889 (Box 54, Reel 2)
  - Christie, James, Cholera Epidemics in East Africa, London, MacMillian and Co., 1876 (Box 54, Reel 3)
  - "Ekiragiro Eryo Busira, 1926, " "Ebiragiro Bya Mugwanya, " M. Kaizi, "Kabaka Daudi Cwa, " Apolo Kagwa, "Ekitabo Ekye Nsenene, " Daudi Cwa, "Okuwuwula Kwa S. Mugwanya, " R.H.W. Pakennam, "Land Tenure, " "Butaka File, Resident's Office, " manuscripts, n.d. (Box 54, Reel 4)
  - Kasirye, Joseph S., "Obulamu Bwa Stanislas Mugwanya, " manuscript, 1955 (Box 54, Reel 5)
  - Leslie, some aspects of African life in Dar es Salaam, report, 1957 (Box 54, Reel 6)
  - Mukasa, Owm. Ham., "Simuda Nyuma, " E.M.K. Mulira, "Sir Apolo Kagwa K.C.M.G. M.B.E., " Apolo Kagwa, "Ekitago Kye Kika Kya Nsenene, " Ali Kulumba, "Ebyafayo By'obusiramu mu Uganda, " manuscripts, n.d. (Box 54, Reel 7)
  - Messing, Simon D., "The Highland Plateau Amhara of Ethiopia, " thesis, University of Pennsylvania, 1957 (Box 54, Reel 8)
- Series XI: Letters of Reference
  Series XI, (Box 55 and 56), contains confidential letters of reference written for students and colleagues. The information contained in this series is restricted and unavailable for research until the year 2024.
  - A, 1962-1973 (Box 55, Folder 1)
  - B, 1957-1973 (Box 55, Folder 2)
  - C-F, 1957-1973 (Box 55, Folder 3)
  - G-H, 1958-1971 (Box 55, Folder 4)
  - I-K, 1957-1973 (Box 55, Folder 5)
  - N-O, 1960-1968 (Box 55, Folder 7)
  - P, 1958-1972 (Box 55, Folder 8)
  - R, 1958-1973 (Box 56, Folder 1)
  - S, 1958-1971 (Box 56, Folder 2-3)
  - T-W, 1957-1973 (Box 56, Folder 4)
  - Y-Z, 1959-1972 (Box 56, Folder 5)